<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Works on Oliver Lehner</title>
    <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Works on Oliver Lehner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 10:09:01 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hörstationen</title>
      <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/hoerstationen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 15:40:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/hoerstationen/</guid>
      <description>The OK Center for Contemporary Art commissioned 5 Hörstationen (Listening Posts) for their 2015 Exhibtion Das Geheimnis der Vögel. The idea was to deliver facts about birds in a playful way to the 100.000 exhibtion visitors. Wooden Boxes, evoking a bird house theme were placed in the exhibition area. A woodpecker sound, played back by a speaker inside the box, would alert passer-bys about the possibility to interact and invite them to inspect the sound source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Players as Producers</title>
      <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/players-as-producers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 18:18:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/players-as-producers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The factory as a metaphor for productivity is the main theme of this folder and the simplistic Blender rendering I created also defined the color palette for the artwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../../pdf/PaP_Folder_Web.pdf&#34;&gt;Folder Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Post</title>
      <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/post-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 15:44:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/post-post/</guid>
      <description>Aw yiss, Neon Pantone Colors! I thought up a three-dimnensional post-post-horn and used its wireframe representation as an eye-catcher. We also recreated the graphic with neon-orange gaffa tape as a larger-than-life tape graffiti in the exhibtion space. I had fun designing this one and it shows!
Folder Download</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speculative Materialities</title>
      <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/speculative-materialities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 15:44:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/speculative-materialities/</guid>
      <description>I designed marketing material for the Interface Culture student exhibition at Ars Electronica 2016. I tackled the challenge to present the manyfold student artworks in a homogenous manner by using elements of a negative space pentagram as an over-arching brand design.
Brochure Download</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skandal Normal</title>
      <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/skandal-normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 15:40:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/skandal-normal/</guid>
      <description>An Art Mediation video commisioned by the OK Center for Contemporary Art Linz for the exhibtion Skandal Normal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LARD</title>
      <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/lard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 09:57:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/lard/</guid>
      <description>Military and police in numerous countries around the globe use Long Range Acoustic Devices (LRADs) as weapons against agitated crowds. LRADs emit a focused sound beam with an intensity that is high enough to permanently damage human hearing. Because it is not desirable for a governmental entity to use weapons, even the non-lethal type, against its own citizens, the manufacturer markets these sonic weapons as “hailing device,” a device that facilitates communication between the authorities and the mob.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopping Mill</title>
      <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/shopping-mill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 09:57:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/shopping-mill/</guid>
      <description>Shopping Mill is an interactive, multi-sensory installation: a treadmill augmented with display and headphones. Walking on the mill simulates a shopping experience with Muzak playback and an endlessly unfolding, 3D-generated shopping aisle. Shopping Mill is a meditation on the relationship between de-realized labor and senseless consumption. A trip into the military entertainment complex. Muzak – the company – was founded by a highly decorated war veteran. Its product was not only developed to make people feel comfortable in uncomfortable architectures but also to heighten attentiveness and productivity in the work place.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>