<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ars Electronica on Oliver Lehner</title>
    <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/tags/ars-electronica/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ars Electronica on Oliver Lehner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Oliver Lehner</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 16:22:05 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/tags/ars-electronica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Through the Far-see-er VR</title>
      <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/farseeer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 16:22:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/farseeer/</guid>
      <description>I contributed a small VR part to Sam Bunn&amp;rsquo;s spectacular utopian Performance/Installation &amp;ldquo;Through the Far-see-er&amp;rdquo;. It is available here but recent changes to motion sensor API could mean your mobile device will not be able to display it correctly. (At the time of this writing, it worked on Firefox v67.0 for Android).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ambisonic Fixations of Error</title>
      <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/ambisonicfixations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 15:40:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/ambisonicfixations/</guid>
      <description>As part of my artistic research of documentation and conservation of sound installations based on consumer VR technology I found it important to investigate gallery soundscapes. With help from Sennheiser Austria and Ars Electronica Festival I recorded ambisonic audio at the festival site and prepared a Web VR Experience to make ephemeral sound art felt after its physical manifestation ceased to exist.
Visit Ambisonic Fixations of Error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Post</title>
      <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/post-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 15:44:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/post-post/</guid>
      <description>Aw yiss, Neon Pantone Colors! I thought up a three-dimnensional post-post-horn and used its wireframe representation as an eye-catcher. We also recreated the graphic with neon-orange gaffa tape as a larger-than-life tape graffiti in the exhibtion space. I had fun designing this one and it shows!
Folder Download</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LARD</title>
      <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/lard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 09:57:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/lard/</guid>
      <description>Military and police in numerous countries around the globe use Long Range Acoustic Devices (LRADs) as weapons against agitated crowds. LRADs emit a focused sound beam with an intensity that is high enough to permanently damage human hearing. Because it is not desirable for a governmental entity to use weapons, even the non-lethal type, against its own citizens, the manufacturer markets these sonic weapons as “hailing device,” a device that facilitates communication between the authorities and the mob.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopping Mill</title>
      <link>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/shopping-mill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 09:57:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oliver-lehner.github.io/creative-portfolio/works/shopping-mill/</guid>
      <description>Shopping Mill is an interactive, multi-sensory installation: a treadmill augmented with display and headphones. Walking on the mill simulates a shopping experience with Muzak playback and an endlessly unfolding, 3D-generated shopping aisle. Shopping Mill is a meditation on the relationship between de-realized labor and senseless consumption. A trip into the military entertainment complex. Muzak – the company – was founded by a highly decorated war veteran. Its product was not only developed to make people feel comfortable in uncomfortable architectures but also to heighten attentiveness and productivity in the work place.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>